hey everyone what is up welcome to the
grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski and on this podcast we
talk about ways for you to grow your
coaching business a membership site
subscription model how to be able to get
people to stick with you stay consistent
and be able to create more money so you
can make 5 10 25 35 50 $100,000 a month
and Beyond we have clients that have
actually made 10 even $20 million I
built my own businesses to over $10
million a year and I want to show you
how you can scale your business
successfully online we're going to talk
about something I've been studying here
recently that I've been applying in my
life and that I've learned I would say
over the course of the last 15 plus
years of being in the space even I got
into the personal development space 21
years ago and I wish I knew these things
before what
if you could tap into the right en to
show up at all times for your content
for writing your sales copy in your
business and how to create more finances
for you and what if it didn't have
anything to do
with weird tactics or maybe you know I I
have talked about how like I I'll
sometimes use video games to get me into
a flow state things like that those are
all cool and all but there's something
else that goes beyond that that I
haven't quite talked about that's more
Rel related to mindset thinking mental
Frameworks that I think you can use and
what if I was able to give you that
mental framework that doesn't use
anything else but how you look at the
world
today and it would affect you positively
to reach your goals faster that's what
we're going to talk about here in this
podcast today is what I have been
looking at related to my own habits my
own behaviors what has been stopping me
and what has been holding me back and
some things that quite frankly I'm
embarrassed about some things that I
look at and I say gosh you know what was
I thinking up to this moment in time and
and and what it is is is this is that we
have a tendency as human beings to have
attachment to things that are emotional
and we have these moments in our life
I've actually been reading this book
this has been inspiring part of this
conversation called The Power of moments
and it talks about how we have es and
flows in moments like they call it in
the book pits and
Peaks and so a pit and a peak might look
like that you have it goes below the
Baseline and above the Baseline negative
experience and positive experience what
is the pit and then what is the peak and
so what we have in life as a human being
is we have these moments that they go
like this and often
times they're very few and far
between but our memories are ATT attach
to a lot of these main moments and what
ends up happening is we end up
remembering and really our personality
starts developing based on what happens
during the high moments and the low
moments okay so I can talk about even my
own experience high and low moments of
you know being able to build a business
over $2 million a year in profit I'm
telling you that was the moment in time
when I felt like I was on top of the
world um and and and and financially I
just felt like I could do anything at
the same time previously to that was
when I was struggling with alcohol and I
ended
up going to jail for drinking and
driving and and that wasn't something
that I was proud of and I learned my
lesson I gosh I don't I actually haven't
drank alcohol in the last three years
and I'm very proud of that fact that's a
high moment for me now right here is
that and the fact that that I can
actually look at multiple moments of my
life where I didn't drink alcohol that
dreams in my life manifested I had a
business that became more successful we
now have two children an amazing
relationship with my wife came out of
two times in moments when I didn't drink
alcohol as well as this moment right
here so I can look at okay drinking
alcohol always seems to correlate to
some of the lowest moments of my life as
far as that goes okay so what ends up
happening is we end up really like
developing a lot of heightened state of
awareness based on these things here's
the problem though okay as human beings
we end up replaying a lot of the
negative occurrences that we have
especially when it comes to our
interactions with people and when it
comes to working with people and
coaching people we have this beautiful
thing in our brain called the reticular
activating system what it does is it
helps the brain sort out uh what is
important and what is not and when
something is more emotionally charged it
shows up more as more important to the
brain unless you can program it to stop
paying attention so much to those things
as far as it goes and it does this on
autopilot why for survival the brain is
very good at keeping you alive but not
thriving okay by
default your your brain and if you live
in society
today uh if you're on social
media your brain is going to be focused
to seek after more do
dopamine more heightened exciting
moments and what ends up happening
though is it really only does so to keep
you alive just enough that you don't go
off the rails and take too much risk
because then you don't want these
negative things to happen as far as this
goes so I can look at in my life the
mistakes that I've made there's wisdom
that I learned there's activities
there's things that I just simply won't
do because otherwise I know that
everything else in my life starts
steering in the wrong direction there's
activities in my life as well that I can
notice that I will do that things start
moving in the directions that I want to
in my life I can tell you growing my
email list in my
business and fully believing in myself
with total confidence in my message and
what's inside of me to where I have
after 21 years believe you know i' I've
been studying what is what does it take
to truly be an expert and a master at
your craft as far as that goes I am
working towards the highest level of
Mastery at what I do as a coach and as a
mentor because I want to be the best in
the world at what I do not so I can say
that I'm the best but for the impact
that that's going to have on my clients
and anybody who follows me knows that
that's exactly what I work towards and
they have seen the progress in that and
thank you for following my journey along
the way in this but what I want to show
you is that I've been learning a few
things in this that we have to do that
will accelerate us on this
Journey our brain ends up dwelling on a
lot of these pits we end up paying
attention to a lot of the negative
things and we end up focusing on what do
we want to avoid what do we not want to
happen repeatedly in our life we don't
want to occur again and again and again
now here's the thing these things that
happened negatively taught us wisdom you
had a a crappy relationship you worked
with a toxic boss you had a client that
was abusive that you might have worked
with and you don't want to work with
clients like that
again so so there's positives and
negatives to this okay so what is the
positive of that moment right there the
positive is that I
recognize red
flags I
notice what I don't want I have
adjusted my marketing to avoid working
with let's just say clients people that
I don't want to work with the problems
with this is that if I'm working so hard
to avoid those people I may actually
repel really good people that I want to
work with because I'm focused so much on
I don't want to run into these people
and here's the other problem that when
we're so focused with our energy and I
want to avoid these people everybody
starts looking like the things that we
want to
avoid everybody starts acting in certain
ways that trigger our red flags and and
we can really start to go crazy with
this to where we're like okay uh
everybody's a red flag FL and nobody's
safe to be around and that's kind of an
extreme way off to the Other Extreme of
like you have no boundaries to where
it's like okay everybody we're blocking
out of our life as far as that goes and
I would say that that there's there's a
healthy balance of you can grow in
strength to where okay I there's
patterns of behavior that if I notice
them in people I'm not going to work
with those people but I can notice that
maybe some of the people that had
certain red flags there were green flags
that they had that as long as somebody
has those green flags but not those red
flags I don't need to avoid those people
that's called wisdom as far as that goes
okay because we can always look at the
good in
people as long as we don't avoid
noticing when the red flags come up and
this is just kind of even a relationship
thing as far as that goes often times
the people that were really meant to
work with have certain traits of very
hard relationships that had that were
very negative and and that's why we're
drawn to those people and so when we
work so hard to avoid people that are
just like
that if we and I noticed this with with
clients that I'm coaching they listen to
me teach and they're like wow you sound
like that coach that screwed me over you
sound like that Mentor that stole all my
money and I'm like I'm not I
promise you know um but I get it because
my marketing I'm sure we Market in a
similar way I'm sure we talk in a
similar way we have a certain Cadence
that we use in a similar way and so when
your brain is so focused so much on what
you're trying to avoid and what you're
trying to uh protect yourself in it
actually starts to project into every
scenario that everybody is like this and
we actually start attracting a lot of
what we don't want because it ends up
becoming a self-fulfilling prophecy as
far as that goes it's again it's part of
the rular activating system we are drawn
like a magnet to the thing that we are
noticing so much about as far as that
goes and we end up even
seeing things that aren't there in
certain situations now again coming back
to this maybe you've been abused youve
had trauma you've dealt with some evil
people terrible people they they exist
right that did they did horrible
things I'm so sorry that happened and we
do not want
to go into sit situations like that
again we need to make sure that we have
boundaries that we don't do that what
I'm encouraging you is this is that that
we're not looking for the good in these
negative people but we're not going to
dwell on we're not going to spend all of
our energy focused on the negative stuff
that we experienced in our past that we
want to avoid
happening and all the negative stuff
that we don't like that's happening in
our life because all we're going to see
is it's a snowball of in our brain our
neurotransmitters they literally start
building new neurological lines inside
of our head that all it sees is this
crappy stuff that's not working out as
far as this goes and so for you to
actually be successful listen we want to
learn the wisdom from this we don't want
to
forget what they did to us what happened
those things we want to avoid those
relationships that we don't want to get
into those nightmare clients that I
don't want to take their money from
right however if all I'm focusing on is
what I what I don't want what I'm not
wanting to attract what I don't want in
my life what's terrible what's horrible
I miss out on
noticing the good exceptional and great
things that are actually all around me
and I believe that all of us actually
have beautiful exceptional amazing
things but the reason why we can't see
it is because we are so focused on the
crappy stuff that's happening one of the
biggest reasons and ways that we can
actually solve this is if we can
heal from the
trauma and heal the pain from the PTSD
that
occurred and actually start to integrate
and heal our personality and heal from
these
experiences to realize that what tried
to break us what tried to hurt
us listen we're still going to have that
boundary we're still going to say I'm
not going
there totally fine that's great but
we're not going to play the victim
anymore we're not going to have a victim
mentality oh they did this to me so
that's why now I am this way all I can
think about is what they did to me
that's what I was dealing with as all I
could think about for like years was
what other people were saying to
me and that what was coming out of me
was trying to defend myself against them
every single time I opened my
mouth until I realized this one
thing that the brain is actually a
really crazy thing that we don't even
fully
understand it exists inside of your
skull and it takes inputs from around
you through your eyeballs through your
your five senses as well as we have
intuition we can feel things we can
sense things there's even things that we
don't understand about it that go so
deep that create our personality our
experiences our beliefs and all of that
and even dive into spirituality as
well but what I found is is this is
that our brain actually creates our
reality
and we actually
cocreate the reality that we're in along
with everybody else who's in our lives
around us along with the people that are
around us as well as along with god with
Holy
Spirit and that all of this works
together in the beautiful creation that
God put together by Design and what's
funny is there's people that are out
there in the tech World they almost look
at it as like is it a simulation are we
living in a computer
simulation because you start to see the
interworkings and the intertwined
stories of how all of this comes
together and there's some sort of an
intelligence that's going on with this
and if you study quantum physics and
entanglement it's like very interesting
how things are not as by mistake as they
look like as far as that goes now
there's free will there's there's
there's choice there's a lot of
randomized chance and things like that
that happens that we don't see
correlations to and we don't
understand not debating that we can't
explain everything we don't know how to
our brain literally only goes based off
of one thing and one thing only our
experiences the stories that we've
learned from other people what we've
established inside of us and our
memories to create the world and the
perspective of the world that we see and
so what ends up happening is if all
you're focused on is the negative you
are dwelling in a world that is just
replaying the negative so you are
actually living in the past have you
ever heard that people say that you're
living in the past and you don't want to
live in the past the reason why people
say that we are living in the past is
because we are literally in our mental
thoughts still there in the situation
where that those bad things happen to us
and so our physical body might literally
be in the Here and Now where none of
that is happening but a projection of
what did happen before is all that we
see and then we end up reacting to it as
if it's happening I'm afraid that I'm
going to lose money with my Facebook ads
I'm afraid that I'm going to lose money
trading stocks I'm afraid that the
housing market and so I'm going to sell
and I'm going to or I'm going to rent or
I'm going to avoid taking risk because I
don't want that thing to happen to me
again and I'm trying to avoid those
things from happening to
me if that's all we're focused on and
that gives me a headache to think about
it really
does freedom comes when you start paying
attention to and visualizing a beautiful
future for yourself what's the life that
you're creating what's the life that I'm
making for my family what are the
beautiful relationships that I have the
connections that I'm developing with
other people and then when my brain
starts going to all the negative see not
the wisdom or the Lessons Learned but
actually where I'm I'm starting to
visualize I'm literally seeing a mental
movie in my mind of how people hurt me I
put a stop sign up where I'm not going
to go back to watching film again I'm
not going to watch that tape I'm not
going to go watch that old TV show in my
head that's trying to program me that
that's the existence or the experience
that I'm experiencing right now because
that is not the life that I choose to
live and so we get to create our reality
based on where we put our Focus so if I
put my focus towards my family and my
friends and building my business and
creating an incredible life for myself
and then towards my faith literally all
the beautiful
amazing things about that that I'm
focusing on starts to come together I
start recognizing opportunities and
ideas and ways that we can put stuff
together and ways to make more money and
ways to do this but if we're so focused
on what we don't have and what we wish
we have see that's the thing part of the
problem is we can either
live in the
past or we can live in the future and
neither of these is helpful this is
called
where we end up not being focused on the
reality because we're only so focused on
a dream so what we need to do is we need
to bring this down
into the
present moment and learn how to be
present with this and this is what a lot
of the work if you're working with a
good therapist somebody who actually
understands how to integrate the mind
and the different parts that we have
from the experiences that we have as
well as learning and training yourself
and disciplining yourself not to escape
to the Future by the way Nostalgia and
future thinking can be a form of
escapism because we don't like what
we're experiencing we're disregulated
our nervous system is always in a state
of chaos and anxiety and when you can
learn to calm that nervous system
down and to be present with the present
moment you can hear clearly the inner
voice that's inside of you what is what
is God speaking to
me what what what what does my intuition
say instead of focusing in on oh I don't
want to I don't want this bad thing to
happen to me here I start noticing what
I need to do today in the here and now
and this week is there a phone call that
I need to make that's going to help me
do I need to go set this up on my
business oh I got a great idea that I
think is going to help me cuz I saw
something on social media that is going
to help me grow my business I found an
event that maybe I'm hosting ing that
that that can teach somebody how to
create an offer Jeremiah has a coaching
program on how to be able to create and
grow my coaching or membership business
maybe I should sign up for that and your
brain starts to focus on the Here and
Now of what you can do right now to take
responsibility for the vision that you
have without a vision without
visualizing your future without the life
you're creating and having hope and
excited
expectation for where you're headed you
won't have motivation we'll struggle
with it we have to every single day
discipline ourselves to go put one foot
in front of the other but can I tell you
this your dreams will happen instead of
you trying to figure out everything in
the future so that you can avoid what's
happening in your past by saying what
can I do
today in the next two minutes in the
next two hours in the next two days days
to move things forward instead of trying
to figure out the next 5 weeks the next
6 months or the next 5 years sure it's
great to have an overarching goal of
that but don't dwell on the past or the
future so much dwell in the present
moment of taking action of what do I got
to do today and tomorrow and how can I
be responsible for where I'm at today to
start to experience the life that I am
creating not by what has been handed to
me
but what I am building because I have
the power to build anything I
imagine you do you really do now might
it take you time sure and that's why we
got to we have to especially if your
dreams or visions are big stay in the
present
moment because otherwise we're going to
be so focused on dreaming about the
future that we never actually do
anything people that make impact they
are doers
who do their dreams but they don't stay
stuck in Dreamland I was somebody who
used to stay stuck in Dreamland all the
time and my mentors used to tell me
Jeremiah you need to you need to bring
it down to earth and I've learned what
that means I used to think bring it down
to earth meant focus on my past and what
has happened and no it actually is be
present and be
responsible and it's interesting having
having one son and another one on the
way has taught me the importance of to
this the responsibility that I have to
my sons and the future that we have and
what's happening with technology and
artificial intelligence and the world
that we're creating and I see the
responsibility that I have to my clients
who've trusted
me to help Point them on what is the
direction to take and the pivots to make
and their businesses to be able to
experience the things that they
want and I believe you can do the same
as well and I'd love to work with you
and help you do that stay plugged into
my podcast subscribe to my YouTube
channel make sure to join if you see
different ads that I'm posting on social
media join some of the live events that
I'm
doing and then when we open the doors to
my accelerator program my Premier
coaching program I'd love to have you in
there to work with you to help you learn
how to bring all of this together with
tangible practical actual proven
stepbystep strategies that work to help
you have the business and the life that
you want this has been grow your life my
name is Jeremiah Kowski and I'll see you
on the episode The Next Episode grow
your life everybody that's what it is
we're growing it and we'll talk soon
have a good one
[Music]
[Applause]